The rising sun painted the baked brick walls of Mohenjo Daro
a warm orange. Maya, a young potter's apprentice, hurried through
the grid like streets, her bare feet padding softly on
the well worn stone. The air hummed with the sounds of life.
The rhythmic clang of metal workers, the chattering of merchants
in the bustling marketplace, the distant bleating of goats.
The great bath beckoned, its cool water promising respite
from the desert heat. Today, Maya hoped to impress
her master with her newest vessel, a clay jar painted with
intricate fish scales, mirroring the bounty the Indus
river provided for their thriving city. Life was predictable,
organized and secure within Mohenjo Daro's well
planned walls.